[music]
>> 6:30 a.m.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Good morning, everyone. It is 6:30 a.m.
I am in Suzhou right now. I caught the
first train out of Shanghai this morning
since I'm doing a day trip and I wanted
to make the most of it. Since it's
currently lotus season, my first stop is
the lotus market. There's so many people
selling beautiful lotus flowers here.
Everything is freshly picked. I really
want to get a bouquet, but I am going to
be walking outside the whole day and I'm
scared the flowers are going to wilt.
So, I don't know. Maybe I'll pick it up
somewhere else.
>> [music]
>> Suzhou is known for their traditional
style pastries. Every single piece is
like a tiny little work of art. It's so
beautiful. They also have samples here.
>> [music]
>> Here for my morning tea. I got a very
nice latte that has "fu" on it, which is
a character for fortune and prosperity.
And then I also have my two pastry
picks. This is the peach blossom pastry
and this is the osmanthus flower pastry.
So beautiful, guys. Look at that. I
haven't eaten since last night and I
feel like I've just been up since
forever. So, it is high time I had a
bite to eat. Cheers.
The inside is is mantis paste. It's a
really nice light floral flavor.
Mhm.
If you guys haven't tried it Chinese
traditional pastries before, you really
need to try it. Like you know French
pastries, they have a little like
like a crunch. Chinese pastries are
super flaky as well, but they're
completely soft. When you bite into it,
it's just pillowy layers [music] of
flakes that
are soft in your mouth and don't make a
sound. But, delicious by the way.
>> [music]
>> I don't know. I just realized I don't
think I've ever had Chinese pastries
with coffee before. It's always with
tea. So, this is a nice little fusion.
Moving on to my favorite, tau hua su.
This is a peach blossom pastry and the
inside filling
I believe this is a rose and red bean
paste filling.
Now, this is what [music] I call a
proper start to the day.
I know quite a few of you guys wanted me
to try the cheongsam rentals and also do
like the cheongsam photo shoot. And
there was like so many of those shops on
the street. Thought about it, but I it's
so hot, guys. I'm like so sticky right
now. I genuinely cannot see myself
trying the cheongsams on one by one,
getting full hair and makeup done, and
then having everything melt off in the
sun as I try my best to control my
expressions for photos. Like for the
past 2 hours, I've just been squinting
like this cuz it's just so sunny. This
Chinese style top that I thrifted the
other day is going to be the closest I'm
going to get to a cheongsam for the time
being, but I will try someday.
>> [music]
>> in a colder month.
I feel energized. I feel refreshed and
we are off to explore a garden.
>> [music]
>> I am from Suzhou canals. It's also super
famous garden. There's a lot of really
beautiful traditional Chinese style
gardens and courtyards here and the most
famous ones are always filled with
tourists. So I decided to come to a
slightly more niche one. It's a lot more
peaceful
and quiet and I can just enjoy the
garden. Look at all these stunning
details in that tiling.
>> [music]
>> Going through a tunnel.
Garden is like a playground. This is so
fun. Now to go down here.
There's actually no way out.
Oh my gosh.
I think I'm stuck in here.
There's like no way out.
Oh my gosh. Wait.
Oh, look at that tree.
They even set up scaffolding to support
the tree cuz it is just like growing so
weird.
>> [music]
>> Look at these bridges.
[music]
>> It's 40 degrees. My face is melting off.
Trying desperately to stay hydrated with
I miss you bing chang. This is literally
just lemon water. This garden is
actually one of the smaller ones, but it
was so so much bigger than I
anticipated. Like I thought it would
just be the size of maybe this like one
courtyard. There was so much to explore
in there, guys. I actually got lost
amongst all the mazes. I am even shocked
myself. These gardens are so well
maintained as well. In the short time
that I've been here, I've seen so many
groundskeepers tending to the plant,
wiping the windows, and even people in
boats making sure that the water is
clear and the lotus flowers are growing
healthily. It's just like so nice to
have this little sliver of history
preserved in modern day like this. It's
[music] such a nice place to come chill.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Just arrived at a restaurant and they
have outdoor seating. It is so freaking
hot outside, but I'm going to sit
outside because it's right by the
canals. I can't not.
Hello.
It is lunchtime. I ordered myself a
feast. I have no idea how I'm going to
finish this much, but I wanted to try a
little bit of everything. So, we have
the Suzhou style noodles over here.
Noodles usually come with some sort of
topping, but because I couldn't decide,
I got the set of nine, which means that
I get to try nine different toppings on
my noodles. I'm guessing this is like
fried fish, some sort of steamed meat,
maybe tofu. These are like little baby
shrimp, very popular topping here.
Mushroom, probably some sort of veggie,
braised pork. I don't know what it's
called in English, but I think in
Chinese it's called tat. It's very fresh
and crunchy. And then, I don't know what
this is, but it looks delicious. They
also gave me a little plate of grapes
and a pot of tea. I'm
Yeah, this is hot tea. I'm like sweating
buckets here, but I shall drink some
tea. When in Suzhou, right?
Gun bei.
Suzhou style noodles are on the thinner
side.
The shrimp is coated in sesame oil or
something. [music] So fragrant and
delicious. Try the fish.
This piece of meat
actually melts in your mouth.
Delicious.
Ta-da!
The staff keeps standing by the window
and checking if I'm okay cuz it's like
really so hot outside. I have like
poking their heads out every 5 minutes
asking if I want to move inside to eat.
But even though the indoor seats also
have a really good view of the canals, I
just want to be right on the water. Am I
weird? I probably am. No one else in
this restaurant is sitting outside.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Walking by the canals after lunch. We're
exploring Pingjiang Road.
All this yummy street food on both
sides.
Cute.
>> [singing]
>> 90% sure I put this contact in the wrong
way round today. It's just been spinning
around in my eye all morning. It feels
so uncomfortable. This is such a nice
street to browse through. There's a lot
of little shops on both sides and
because everyone's dressed up, it's like
>> [music]
>> a very nice view on the streets.
These alleyways are like full of hair
and makeup stores so that you can get
your entire look done to match your fit.
So convenient. Also just like
photographers roaming the streets just
waiting to take photos for you. So if
you want to get nice photos, definitely
come to China.
>> [music]
>> Look at these gorgeous teacups.
They have teacups here with surnames on
them and I found mine.
>> [music]
>> Look at these.
>> Yeah, jasmine ice cream to cool down in
this heat.
Mhm. The outside is coated in like dried
jasmine flowers, I think.
Mhm. It is melting so fast.
Actually fighting for my life right now.
Like look how much is dripping. It's all
over my top.
Just imagining myself in the background
of everybody's photo shoots with ice
cream down my shirt and on my chin.
Not a pleasant sight.
Mhm. Okay, I just cleaned up a bit.
Hopefully this doesn't stain. Right now
I just have like a huge wet patch at the
front of my shirt. That was the most
stressful ice cream eating experience
I've ever had. Like it's never melted on
me that fast before.
Jasmine flower that is done best to cut
it.
I got a jasmine flower bracelet to lift
my mood. Smells so nice. These are real
jasmine flowers and the grandma said
that once it dries out, it'll last for
30 days. So, we shall see about that,
but I'll be happy enough with just one
day.
>> [music]
>> The doorways here are all so pretty.
I've just been walking in the sun the
entire day and I feel my skin is burning
up. I sunburn so easily, guys, which is
why even on the sunniest days, I'll
usually have my entire body covered, but
today I didn't have anything that would
match this top and I also intended on
bringing sunscreen, but obviously I
forgot. So, instead I have brought out
my mini sunbrella.
Give me a sec, guys. I'm currently
trying to find a cafe. Right now it's
like the hottest part of the day and no
person in their right mind should be
outside. I think it's down this road.
Okay.
Do you see what I see? Look at that. A
secret matcha lake hidden right in the
middle of Sujo.
How beautiful.
Wow.
>> [music]
>> Oh my god. Gosh, this place is so cute.
Ordered a pistachio latte. It also came
with some pistachios and a little intro
card. It has pistachio butter, pistachio
cold foam on top, coconut cream, coconut
milk, normal milk, and espresso shot in
it.
Drink half of it in one go. like
drink half of it in one go. Okay.
>> [music]
>> Very good. It was more savory than I
expected. Like I think there was a pinch
of salt in there or something.
I'm literally eating ice right now. But
I also feel like I would have preferred
a matcha latte.
>> [music]
>> Second street food of the day. This time
I got an orange juice. This is so
refreshing though. I do recommend.
I found another place to sit down.
Already no more of this. Going to rest
for a bit and then go check out Xiangta
Shiji. These are like local markets but
they've been newly renovated so
everything is really nice and pretty.
Yeah.
Came up for the food section and
specifically for this bowl of taro mochi
balls. Look at this. [music]
>> [music]
>> How's that? So this is like a taro and
probably sweet potato puree. And they
have added this like loopy mochi in the
middle as well as these tiny little
glutinous rice balls. It is the perfect
level of sweetness.
Which is just like
very lightly sweet. Enough to bring out
the natural flavor of the taro. [music]
It's meant to be sour.
Amazing. Not hungry at all. I'm so full
from lunch and also all the liquid I've
just been drinking.
I'm pretty sure I
Guess what I see.
Should I get a bunch? Should I get a
bunch?
>> [music]
[laughter]
>> That's my purse.
This huge bouquet was 20 yen.
It is sunset right now and I have made
it to the iconic Shilin Shen Tang
Street. This is another place with like
really pretty canal views. It's super
beautiful lit up at night. I just need
to figure out how to cross the road
right now cuz the side with all the
lanterns is on the other side.
>> [music]
>> I do not do well in places that are this
crowded. Trying to kill time right now
because I want to film the lanterns
lighting up at night. There's a lot of
really cute shops here but my hands are
full and my tummy is also full. Have a
look around. [music] There's a lot of
really yummy food.
>> [music]
[music]